<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Jason Rohweder</origin>
				<origin>James Rogala</origin>
				<origin>Janis Ruhser</origin>
				<pubdate>20180130</pubdate>
				<title>2010/11 Level 3 Aquatic Areas - Upper Mississippi River System</title>
				<geoform>Vector Digital Data Set (Polygon)</geoform>
				<onlink>https://doi.org/10.5066/F7Z89BMP</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>
The U.S. Geological Survey's Upper Midwest Environmental Sciences Center (UMESC) created high-resolution land cover/use data sets for the Upper Mississippi River System (UMRS). Aerial images of Pools 3-13 Upper Mississippi River System and Pools, Alton-Marseilles, Illinois River were collected in color infrared (CIR) in August of 2010 at 8”/pixel and 16”/pixel respectively using a mapping-grade Applanix DSS 439 digital aerial camera. In August 2011, CIR aerial images of Pools 14-Open River South, Upper Mississippi River and Dresden pool, Illinois River were collected at 16”/pixel with the same camera. The CIR aerial images were interpreted and automated using a 31-class LTRM vegetation classification. These data have been used to create a variety of products, one of which is a data set used to classify aquatic areas. The 2010/11 aquatic areas data sets were created by first generalizing the available land cover/use data into a land/water data set, then reinterpreting the areas classified as water to determine the type of aquatic area. This level 1 aquatic areas data set was then further modified to produce the level 2 aquatic areas data set for those pools that have had bathymetric data collected including pools 3-26 and the open river reach of the Upper Mississippi River, and the Illinois River from the Dresden Pool to the Alton Pool.

    The purpose of the level 3 classification procedure was to add metrics describing connectivity, depth, and structures to each polygon in the level 2 aquatic areas dataset. These metrics provide useful information for quantifying habitat for a wide-range of species. This product only contains polygons identified as Structure Channel Border, Unstructured Channel Border, Contiguous Floodplain Lake, Side Channel, and Tertiary Channel.

    In addition, the channel border class was further reclassified for level 3 according to the presence of river training structures.  River training structures were obtained from the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Inland Electronic Navigation Chart.
</abstract>
			<purpose>The Upper Midwest Environmental Sciences Center administers the US Army Corps of Engineers' Upper Mississippi River Restoration (UMRR) Program, Long Term Resource Monitoring (LTRM) element, authorized under the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (Public Law 99-662). The mission of the UMRR-LTRM is to provide decision-makers with information to maintain the Upper Mississippi River System (UMRS) as a viable large river ecosystem given its multiple-use character. The long-term goals of the program are to understand the system, determine resource trends and impacts, develop management alternatives, manage information, and develop useful products. The creation and distribution of aquatic areas data for the UMRS aids the Center in meeting these goals through the Habitat Needs Assessment II (HNA-II) project. The HNA-II will utilize many new data and information products, as well as modeling approaches that were stated as limitations of HNA-I. In addition, previous efforts to document desired future conditions of the UMRS will be incorporated into the assessment. Finally, additional input from river resources and other technical teams will help guide the process.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<rngdates>
					<begdate>20100801</begdate>
					<enddate>20110831</enddate>
				</rngdates>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>None planned</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-92.883397903</westbc>
				<eastbc>-87.837456436</eastbc>
				<northbc>44.761555848</northbc>
				<southbc>36.941222757</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>Main Channel</themekey>
				<themekey>Backwater</themekey>
				<themekey>Impoundment</themekey>
				<themekey>Navigation Channel</themekey>
				<themekey>Shallow Floodplain</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>Alexandria Digital Library Feature Type Thesaurus</themekt>
				<themekey>wetlands</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>USGS Thesaurus</themekt>
				<themekey>water resource management</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>Mississippi River</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>Common geographic areas</placekt>
				<placekey>Wisconsin</placekey>
				<placekey>Minnesota</placekey>
				<placekey>Illinois</placekey>
				<placekey>Missouri</placekey>
				<placekey>Iowa</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<useconst>None</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, Midwest Region</cntorg>
					<cntper>Jason Rohweder</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Biologist</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>2630 Fanta Reed Road</address>
					<city>La Crosse</city>
					<state>WI</state>
					<postal>54603</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>608-781-6228</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>608-783-6066</cntfax>
				<cntemail>jrohweder@usgs.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<datacred>US Army Corps of Engineers' Upper Mississippi River Restoration Program- Long Term Resource Monitoring element and USGS's Upper Midwest Environmental Sciences Center</datacred>
		<native>Environment as of Metadata Creation: Microsoft [Unknown] Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.5 (Build 6491) Service Pack N/A (Build N/A)</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>A check is performed to ensure every polygon has an attribute code and that it is a valid code.</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>All polygon features are checked for topology using ArcGIS.</logic>
		<complete>All data that were photo-interpreted were also automated.</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>The horizontal positional accuracy was tested against the base layer land cover/use data. No additional tests were performed.</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
			<vertacc>
				<vertaccr>Not applicable.</vertaccr>
			</vertacc>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>UMESC</origin>
						<pubdate>19951212</pubdate>
						<title>1989-91 Aquatic Habitats - Upper Mississippi River System</title>
						<geoform>Vector Digital Data Set</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>La Crosse, WI</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://umesc.usgs.gov/data_library/aqa_feat_bath_str/aquatic_areas.html</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>1989</begdate>
							<enddate>1991</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>Aqa orig</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Source information for the original Main Navigation Channel and Channel Border polygons</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>UMESC</origin>
						<pubdate>20111221</pubdate>
						<title>UMRS LTRMP 2010/11 LCU Mapping</title>
						<geoform>Vector Digital Data Set</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>La Crosse, WI</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://www.umesc.usgs.gov/data_library/land_cover_use</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>20100801</begdate>
							<enddate>20110831</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>2010/11 LCU</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Source information used in land/water dissolve.  Also used to calculate vegetation overlap and edge statistics (wet forest, aquatic veg)</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>United States Army Corps of Engineers - Army Geospatial Center</origin>
						<pubdate>20140113</pubdate>
						<title>Inland Electronic Navigation Chart</title>
						<geoform>Vector Digital Data Set</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Alexandria, VA</pubplace>
							<publish>United States Army Corps of Engineers - Army Geospatial Center</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://www.agc.army.mil/Missions/Echarts.aspx</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>unknown</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>IENC</srccitea>
				<srccontr>IENC used for Main Navigation Channel and Channel Border, also for river training structures, and revetments.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Army Corps of Engineers’ Upper Mississippi River Restoration (UMRR) Program Long Term Resource Monitoring (LTRM) element, as distributed by the U.S. Geological Survey, Upper Midwest Environmental Sciences Center, La Crosse, Wisconsin</origin>
						<pubdate>20160624</pubdate>
						<title>Upper Mississippi River Restoration (UMRR) Program Topobathy</title>
						<geoform>Raster Digital Data Set</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>La Crosse, WI</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey - ScienceBase</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>https://www.sciencebase.gov/catalog/item/5589ae19e4b0b6d21dd63942</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>1989</begdate>
							<enddate>2011</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>topobath</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Used to classify aquatic area polygons according to water depth.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>USACE Districts (St. Paul, Rock Island, St. Louis)</origin>
						<pubdate>20170701</pubdate>
						<title>UMRS river gage data</title>
						<geoform>Observed/Measured First-Hand</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>St. Paul, MN; Rock Island, IL; St. Louis, MO</pubplace>
							<publish>US Army Corps of Engineers</publish>
						</pubinfo>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>Digital and/or Hardcopy Resources</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>19720101</begdate>
							<enddate>20111231</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>observed</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>gage_data</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Used to develop water surface elevation profiles reflecting conditions of the 25th percentile for the period 1972-2011 (i.e., equivalent to the condition exceeded 75% of the time in the 40-yr period).</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>The 2010/11 Land Cover/Land Use dataset was used as the basis for the land/water dissolve.</procdesc>
				<procdate>20160801</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>
The Main Navigation Channel and Channel Border polygons were copied from the original 1989 Aquatic Areas and appended to the land/water dissolve. The rest of the Aquatic Areas were attributed on screen, with polygon boundaries delineated where necessary, according to a generalized version of the classification described here:
     http://www.umesc.usgs.gov/documents/reports/1993/93t003.pdf Wilcox, D. B. 1993. An aquatic habitat classification system for the Upper Mississippi River System. U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Environmental Management Technical Center, Onalaska, Wisconsin. EMTC 93-T003. 9 pp. + Appendix A.
     No minimum mapping unit was defined for the aquatic areas, with the exception of Contiguous Floodplain Lake (CFL) which shall not be delineated when smaller than 0.04 ha.
</procdesc>
				<procdate>20160915</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>The original Main Navigation Channel was adjusted where it appeared to cross structures, islands, or shorelines. Channel Border polygons were also adjusted to encompass structures, smooth borders to other aquatic areas, and extend to shorelines where applicable. The United States Army Corps of Engineers - Army Geospatial Center - Inland Electronic Navigation Chart was used to assist in these delineations.</procdesc>
				<procdate>20160915</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Bathymetric and land cover data and automated approaches were used to reclassify select level 1 classes for level 2.  In addition, all of the CFSA class was reclassified to CFL or SC, and parts of the CIMP class were reclassified to CFL or SC. Also, side channels were further classified into both SC and also tertiary channels (TSC).</procdesc>
				<procdate>20170930</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>The channel border class from level 2 was further reclassified for level 3 according to the presence of river training structures.  River training structures were obtained from the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Inland Electronic Navigation Chart.  Areas of channel border within 400 meters of a river training structure were reclassified as "Structured Channel Border" and those that were not were reclassified as "Unstructured Channel Border".</procdesc>
				<procdate>20170930</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>To produce the level 3 aquatic areas product several scripts were developed in python to calculate the metrics within ArcMap 10.5.  Individual scripts were developed for the lentic aquatic area types and also for the lotic aquatic area types.</procdesc>
				<procdate>20170930</procdate>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>UMRR topobathy and UMRS river gage data were used to generate bathymetry at a selected water surface elevation profile. That profile was developed from statistical analysis of gage data to determine the condition based on percentiles of a 40-yr period, and then linear interpolation between gages was performed spatially in a raster database. Adjustments for disconnectedness with the main channel where addressed. The topobathy elevation values were subtracted from the raster of water surface elevation to generate bathymetry for the selected condition. Metrics related to water depth were produced from this bathymetry data.</procdesc>
				<procdate>20170730</procdate>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct>Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf></ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<planar>
				<planci>
					<plance>coordinate pair</plance>
					<coordrep>
						<absres>0.6096</absres>
						<ordres>0.6096</ordres>
					</coordrep>
					<plandu>Meter</plandu>
				</planci>
			</planar>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>D_North_American_1983</horizdn>
				<ellips>GRS_1980</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="aqa_2010_lvl3_011918">
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>Attribute Table</enttypl>
				<enttypd>Table containing attribute information associated with the data set.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>Producer defined</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>1</rdommin>
						<rdommax>5652</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>uniq_id</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Unique identifier supplied for each individual aquatic area polygon.  Developed by concatenating a three-digit pool abbreviation, the aquatic area code, and a number (i.e., P04_TSC_12)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Unique identifier supplied for each individual aquatic area polygon.  Developed by concatenating a three-digit pool abbreviation, the aquatic area code, and a number (i.e., P04_TSC_12)</udom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>aa_num</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Unique number supplied to individual aquatic area polygon type and pool.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>1</rdommin>
						<rdommax>3401</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>AQUA_CODE</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Codes designating Aquatic Area features</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>CFL</edomv>
						<edomvd>Contiguous Floodplain Lake</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>SC</edomv>
						<edomvd>Side Channel</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>SCB</edomv>
						<edomvd>Structured Channel Border</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>TSC</edomv>
						<edomvd>Tertiary Channel</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>USCB</edomv>
						<edomvd>Unstructured Channel Border</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>AQUA_DESC</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Text description of the AQUA_CODE attribute, self-explained in the fields.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Contiguous Floodplain Lake</edomv>
						<edomvd>
Lakes connected by apparent surface flow to channels.

       Each navigation reach may contain zero to many CFL polygons, which are delineated with a straight line across the connection to the channel, as a continuation of the apparent shorelines. Determination of CFL vs. IFL (see below) can be highly dependent on water levels at the time of aerial photography, image resolution, and/or the minimum mapping unit used to delineate land cover features.
</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Side Channel</edomv>
						<edomvd>
Channels other than the main channel. 

       Navigation reaches may contain zero to many SC polygons, delineated with straight/diagonal lines from the shoreline to the apex of an island polygon at upstream and downstream limits of the apparent channels.
</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Structured Channel Border</edomv>
						<edomvd>Areas within the channel border that contain river training structures.  This is calculated by selecting individual channel border segments, then selecting river training structures that intersect that channel border segment.  Next, the river training structures are buffered 400 meters, clipped by the channel border polygon and then the buffers that overlap are combined to form the structured channel border segment.</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Tertiary Channel</edomv>
						<edomvd>Side channels that are not directly connected to the main channel were generally reclassified as TSC. This Level 2 classification of SC was primarily done to create natural segments that allow for adding metrics in Level 3. The loose definition of TSC warrants some caution in its use as a standalone class in Level 2, and collapsing TSC back into SC is recommended if using Level 2 in a standalone manner (i.e., using without metrics from Level 3).</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>Unstructured Channel Border</edomv>
						<edomvd>Areas within the channel border that are at least 400 meters from a river training structure.</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pool</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>3-digit code defining the navigation pool that each aquatic area polygon falls within</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>ALT</edomv>
						<edomvd>Alton Pool - Illinois River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>DRE</edomv>
						<edomvd>Dresden Pool - Illinois River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>LAG</edomv>
						<edomvd>La Grange Pool - Illinois River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>MAR</edomv>
						<edomvd>Marseilles Pool - Illinois River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>OR1</edomv>
						<edomvd>Upper Open River Pool - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>OR2</edomv>
						<edomvd>Lower Open River Pool - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P03</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 3 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P04</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 4 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P05</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 5 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P06</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 6 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P07</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 7 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P08</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 8 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P09</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 9 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P10</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 10 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P11</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 11 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P12</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 12 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P13</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 13 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P14</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 14 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P15</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 15 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P16</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 16 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P17</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 17 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P18</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 18 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P19</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 19 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P20</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 20 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P21</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 21 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P22</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 22 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P24</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 24 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P25</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 25 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P26</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 26 - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>P5A</edomv>
						<edomvd>Pool 5A - Mississippi River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>PEO</edomv>
						<edomvd>Peoria Pool - Illinois River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrdomv>
					<edom>
						<edomv>STA</edomv>
						<edomvd>Starved Rock Pool - Illinois River</edomvd>
						<edomvds>Producer defined</edomvds>
					</edom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Area</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of polygon in square meters</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>44.5096359085</rdommin>
						<rdommax>34306969.4502</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Square meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Perimeter</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Perimeter of polygon in meters</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>31.8299003473</rdommin>
						<rdommax>253065.268774</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Acres</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of polygon in acres</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0.0109985705601</rdommin>
						<rdommax>8477.43677298</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Acres</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>Hectares</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of polygon in hectares</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0.00445096359085</rdommin>
						<rdommax>3430.69694502</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Hectares</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>bath_pct</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region that is covered by 75% exceedance bathymetry raster surface</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>123.935249249</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>max_depth</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Maximum depth of 75% exceedance bathymetry within aquatic area region measured in meters. (-9999 denotes absence of 75% exceedance bathymetric data within polygon)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>139.67</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>avg_depth</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Average depth of 75% exceedance bathymetry within aquatic area region measured in meters.  (-9999 denotes absence of 75% exceedance bathymetric data within polygon)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>11.5412920239</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>sd_depth</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Standard deviation of depth of 75% exceedance bathymetry within aquatic area region measured in meters.  (-9999 denotes absence of 75% exceedance bathymetric data within polygon)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>5.53299662572</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>tot_vol</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Total bathymetric volume (at 75% exceedance level) within aquatic area region measured in meters3.  (-9999 denotes absence of 75% exceedance bathymetric data within polygon)</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>75380141.25</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters3</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_gt50</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area within aquatic area region that has depth greater than 50 centimeters measured in square meters.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>32298702.7741</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_gt100</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area within aquatic area region that has depth greater than 1 meter measured in square meters.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>24240452.7572</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_gt200</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area within aquatic area region that has depth greater than 2 meters measured in square meters.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>12622768.4024</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_gt300</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area within aquatic area region that has depth greater than 3 meters measured in square meters.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>11691025.9416</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>avg_fetch</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>A weighted (based on occurrence of historical wind direction) mean fetch in kilometers.  Only developed for lentic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lotic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>3.67288217821</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Kilometers</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>sdi</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>(Shoreline development index) The ratio of the region perimeter (including lotic and lentic connections) to the perimeter of a circle of the same area as the region</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>25.8882924173</rdommax>
						<attrunit>ratio</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>econ</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>(Effective connections) The ratio of the length of the longest segment of terrestrial shoreline to the total terrestrial shoreline length.  Only developed for lentic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lotic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>91.5366537428</rdommax>
						<attrunit>ratio</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>sill</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Total area in meters2 that meets the definition of a depression at 4 levels (1, 1.5, 2, and 3 meters deep),  Only developed for lentic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lotic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>2741045.67153</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>min_rm</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Minimum river mile value of aquatic area region.  Values of -9999 denote the aquatic area polygon was outside of the river mile raster used to calculate the metric.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>815.21105957</rdommax>
						<attrunit>River Mile</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>max_rm</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Maximum river mile value of aquatic area region.  Values of -9999 denote the aquatic area polygon was outside of the river mile raster used to calculate the metric.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>815.340087891</rdommax>
						<attrunit>River Mile</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>len_met</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Distance in meters between minimum river mile and maximum river mile values of aquatic area region.  Values of -9999 denote the aquatic area polygon was outside of the river mile raster used to calculate the metric.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>124576.977098</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>len_outl</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to other aquatic area polygons classified as lotic (main navigation channel, channel border, tributary channel, side channel, or tertiary side channel).  This metric was not calculated for channel border aquatic area polygons and were given a value of -9999.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>49178.6274123</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_outl</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to other aquatic area polygons classified as lotic (main navigation channel, channel border, tributary channel, side channel, or tertiary side channel). This metric was not calculated for channel border aquatic area polygons and were given a value of -9999.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100.000000001</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>num_outl</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Total number of lotic outlets from aquatic area region (adjacent polygons defined as main navigation channel, channel border, tributary channel, side channel, or tertiary side channel). This metric was not calculated for channel border aquatic area polygons and were given a value of -9999.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>66</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>len_oute</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to aquatic area polygons classified as lentic (contiguous floodplain lake, isolated floodplain lake, or contiguous impounded).</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>26639.2332537</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_oute</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to aquatic area polygons classified as lentic (contiguous floodplain lake, isolated floodplain lake, or contiguous impounded).</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100.000000082</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>num_oute</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Total number of lentic outlets from aquatic area region (adjacent polygons defined as contiguous floodplain lake, isolated floodplain lake, or contiguous impounded).</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>90</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_aqveg</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region classified as aquatic vegetation in 2010/2011 land cover land use.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-2.37245560015E-05</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_opwat</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region classified as open water in 2010/2011 land cover land use.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100.000023725</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>len_terr</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to polygons defined as "terrestrial"</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>132356.093274</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_terr</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to polygons defined as "terrestrial".</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_chan</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to polygons defined as "aquatic".</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-4.55997906101E-10</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>len_wetf</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to wet forest. Land cover/land use developed in 2010/2011 by the Long Term Resource Monitoring element was used to determine adjacent land cover types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>115660.947501</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct1wetf</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region's perimeter adjacent to wet forest.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>99.9196385403</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct2wetf</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region's terrestrial shoreline adjacent to wet forest.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>0</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>len_wd</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of river training structures overlapping aquatic area region in meters. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>11174.2682151</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>wdl_p_m2</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of river training structures overlapping aquatic area region in meters divided by total area of aquatic area region in meters2.   Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>0.0210910128881</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters per meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>num_wd</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Number of river training structures (wing dikes, bendway weirs, etc) that overlap aquatic area region.  Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>82</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>sco_wd</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>River training tructures with scour holes within 50 meters as defined by topographic position index classification. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>69</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>psco_wd</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of river training structures with scour holes within 50 meters. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>100</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>len_revln</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of revetted bank (concrete or loose stone) within 20 meters of the aquatic area region in meters.  Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>13285.7391673</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>rev_p_m2</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Length of revetted bank within 20 meters of the aquatic region in meters divided by the aquatic area region's area.   Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>0.107818446763</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters per meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>num_rev</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Total number of revetments within 20 meters of the aquatic region.  Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>37</rdommax>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_rev</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of terrestrial shoreline that is revetted.  Calculated according to the formula: (Length of revetments within 20 meters of aquatic area region divided by length of terrestrial shoreline) * 100. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>2695.82819575</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_rev2</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Percent of aquatic area region perimeter that is revetted. Calculated according to the formula: (Length of revetments within 20 meters of aquatic area region divided by length of aquatic area region perimeter) * 100. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>338.453295008</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_tpi1</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of aquatic area region classified as “canyon bottom” according to topographic position index. Topographic position index outputs developed using Land Facet Corridor Designer (Jenness 2013). Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>398622</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_tpi1</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Pct of aquatic area region classified as “canyon bottom” according to topographic position index.  Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>41.9236193957</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_tpi2</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of aquatic area region classified as “flat/gentle” according to topographic position index. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>15099549</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_tpi2</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Pct of aquatic area region classified as “flat/gentle” according to topographic position index. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>724.6837781</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_tpi3</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of aquatic area region classified as “steep slope” according to topographic position index. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>435313</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_tpi3</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Pct of aquatic area region classified as “steep slope” according to topographic position index. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>41.6577802014</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>area_tpi4</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Area of aquatic area region classified as “ridgetop” according to topographic position index. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>1883564</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Meters2</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>pct_tpi4</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Pct of aquatic area region classified as “ridgetop” according to topographic position index. Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>95.8843715664</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Percent</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>sinuosity</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Polygonal sinuosity of the aquatic area region.  Values approaching 1 are more sinuous, approaching 0 are less sinuous (Tim Fox unpublished).  Only developed for lotic aquatic area polygon types.  A value of -9999 supplied for lentic aquatic area poilygon types.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>-9999</rdommin>
						<rdommax>0.81429661327</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Sinuosity index</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>year_phot</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Year of photography that aquatic area delineations were based upon.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Producer defined</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<rdom>
						<rdommin>2010</rdommin>
						<rdommax>2011</rdommax>
						<attrunit>Year</attrunit>
					</rdom>
				</attrdomv>
			</attr>
		</detailed>
		<overview>
			<eaover>The entity and attribute information provided here describes the tabular data associated with the data set. Please review the detailed descriptions that are provided (the individual attribute descriptions) for information on the values that appear as fields/table entries of the data set.</eaover>
			<eadetcit>The entity and attribute information was generated by the individual and/or agency identified as the originator of the data set. Please review the rest of the metadata record for additional details and information.</eadetcit>
		</overview>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntper>GS ScienceBase</cntper>
					<cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>Denver Federal Center, Building 810, Mail Stop 302</address>
					<city>Denver</city>
					<state>CO</state>
					<postal>80225</postal>
					<country>United States</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>888-275-8747</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>sciencebase@usgs.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<distliab>Unless otherwise stated, all data, metadata and related materials are considered to satisfy the quality standards relative to the purpose for which the data were collected. Although these data and associated metadata have been reviewed for accuracy and completeness and approved for release by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS), no warranty expressed or implied is made regarding the display or utility of the data on any other system or for general or scientific purposes, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty.</distliab>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20180130</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey, Midwest Region</cntorg>
					<cntper>Jason Rohweder</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Biologist</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>2630 Fanta Reed Road</address>
					<city>La Crosse</city>
					<state>WI</state>
					<postal>54603</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>608-781-6228</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>608-783-6066</cntfax>
				<cntemail>jrohweder@usgs.gov</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
	</metainfo>
	<Esri><CreaDate>20180817</CreaDate><CreaTime>14521300</CreaTime><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><DataProperties><itemProps><itemLocation><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\IGSARFEBLTMVA00\C$\CWD_fish\DataSets_7_7\aqa_2010_lvl3_011918</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></itemLocation></itemProps><copyHistory><copy source="C:\CWD_fish\aqa_2010_lvl3_011918" dest="\\IGSARFEBLTMVA00\C$\CWD_fish\DataSets_7_7\aqa_2010_lvl3_011918" date="20180707" time="09232200"></copy></copyHistory></DataProperties><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat></Esri></metadata>
